旁白:成长的烦恼前情提要…
Narrator: Last time on Growing Pains...
杰森:现在西维尔一家要开家庭会议,人人都得参加,
Jason: It's time for another Seaver family meeting and none of you's going
谁也不准缺席.
anywhere.
本:爸爸想组织全家去渡假.
Ben: Dad wanted a family vacation.
杰森:看把你们给吓的?到底是要去佛罗里达呢?
Jason: Takes your breath away, doesn't it?
还是……
So what's it gonna be folks, Florida, or...
本:毛利岛!毛利岛!爸爸以为去毛利岛我们大家都非常高兴.
Ben: Maui! Maui! He thought we were all excited about the idea.
迈克:一定会不虚此行!!
Mike: Maui would be okay!
本:麻烦总是恭候你的到来.啊,快过来!快点!
Ben: But, there was trouble ahead. Oh boy, oh boy oh boy, a shark!
快点呀!鲨鱼!妈妈忙碌了一天之后还得赶稿子.
Mom had to work on a story.
杰森:我终于明白为什么你总是萎靡不振了!
Jason: That explains why you've been too tired to socialize.
开萝尔:是吗?!我也很喜欢历史!
Carol: Yea, I love history too!
本:开萝尔在这找到了新男友,
Ben: Carol found there was another fish in the sea,
而迈克也把一个夏威夷姑娘泡到了手!
while Mike enjoyed the local culture.
玛利亚:瞧瞧,有人没付钱就想参加旅行团!!
Malia: Look like someone's joined my tour without paying.
迈克:嗨!你干嘛老是针对我?
Mike: Hey, how'd you spot me?
玛利亚:嘿,你什么都没带就出来混?
Malia: Aloha, Mike. Did you remember to bring your trunks?
迈克:是啊,只想着你了,别的什么都忘了!
Mike: Hey, I haven't been able to think about anything else.
本:今晚,就在今晚,不知毛利岛上会发生什么事.
Ben: So tonight, let's see what happens to our vacation in Maui.
迈克:嗨,你打算带我去哪?
Mike: Uh, where are you taking me?
玛利亚:定会让你开心的,走吧,快点!!
Malia: Someplace neat. Come on. Come on.
迈克:嗯!!你看这不是坟地吗!
Mike: Uh, well you know, there's dead people here.
玛利亚:当然!我曾祖父,曾祖父的父亲,还有我姑奶奶劳姬…..
Malia: Sure. My great grandfather, his father, my great aunt Loki.
迈克:嗯,我明白,
Mike: Yeah, well, you know I'm sure they're very nice people.
他们生前都是好人,行端品直.
Uh, polite, well behaved.
玛利亚:别说话,跟着我就行了.
Malia: Just follow me.
迈克:我们到底要去哪??
Mike: Look, where are we going?
玛利亚:升天啊!
Malia: To heaven.
迈克:你这话是啥意思?!!
Mike: Exactly how do you mean that?
迈克:哇塞!
Mike: Wow!
玛利亚:这里就是我的海滩,
Malia: This is my beach.
迈克:你买下了?!
Mike: You own this?
玛利亚:这片海滩属于每一个人.
Malia: Everybody owns this.
迈克:没错,就像国家公园.我们长岛那边也有这样的公园,
Mike: Oh yeah, you know that's kind of like a state park.
可总是人满为患.这里就不同,沙滩,
See, we got those in Long Island.
贝壳,各式建筑,
But there's so many people and all the graffiti all over the place.
夕阳,还有美女,搭配在一起给人一种胜似仙境的感觉.
This is a great beach, you know, I mean, you got sand and shells, the works.
玛利亚:你紧张兮兮的干嘛?
Malia: Why are you so nervous?
迈克:没有啊!我哪有紧张!
Mike: I'm not, I'm not nervous. I'm not nervous.
玛利亚:是不是我们单独呆在一起的时间不长的缘故?
Malia: Is it because you haven't spent much time alone with me?
迈克:嗨,怎么老拿我开涮!我是说,
Mike: Um, what're you kidding?
嗯,好了,
I mean, well, yea,
你说得对,我们独处的时间是不多,那有怎样?
I guess you can say that I haven't spent nearly enough time with you.
玛利亚:没什么,你能这么说,
Malia: It's ok, I like that.
我反而觉得高兴.因为很多从岛外来这的男孩老是夸夸其谈,好像他们什么都懂,
Usually boys from the mainland talk to me like they know everything and
而我什么都不知道一样,原因则是我生来就住在这.
I know nothing just because I spent my whole life here.
迈克:这样啊,那你放心好了,我比你遇到的任何男孩都懂得少.
Mike: Oh well, trust me, I know less than any guy you ever met.
玛利亚:谢谢!你的意思我明白!
Malia: I sense that about you.
迈克:从你说"Aloha"开始,
Mike: You know, I sense something about you too.
我就对你一见钟情.
From the moment you said Aloha.
玛利亚:我可以再说一遍的."Aloha",迈克!
Malia: I can say it again. Aloha Mike.
Mike: Aloha, Malia. Oh wait a minute, what are you doing
玛利亚:游泳啊!你可说过你穿着泳裤的,是不是?
Malia: I'm going swimming. You did say you brought your trunks, didn't you?
迈克:嗯,没错!
Mike: Oh, uh, right.
杰森:这是什么呀?
Jason: What's this?
服务生:中空的菠萝,里面灌了酒.
Waiter: This is a hollowed out pineapple with booze in it.
你以为是什么?
What did you think it was, a thermonuclear device?
战胜:我可没要这道采!
Jason: I didn't order that.
服务生:没事,不用您付钱,这是那位女士送给您的!
Waiter: But the lady in the front corner sent it.
杰森:我结婚了.
Jason: I'm married.
服务生:就是那边的金发女郎.瞧瞧,她不是过来了吗?!
Waiter: A blonde twinkie over there. Oh right, here she comes.
麦琪:帅哥你好,我叫罗克西.
Maggie: Hi, good looking. I'm Roxy.
杰森:我是劳埃.
Jason: I'm Raul.
服务生:泰德.
Waiter: I'm Ted.
杰森:想来一杯吗?
Jason: Can I buy you one of those?
麦琪:谢谢!
Maggie: Anytime.
杰森:你住在这岛上?
Jason: So do you, um, live here?
麦琪:当然不是,这里是旅馆,
Maggie: Of course not, this is a hotel. Get in the game.
我自然可以随便来,不过我是过来探望家人的.
No, no, actually I am here visiting with my family.
杰森:真的吗?我也是啊!
Jason: Are you really? Me too.
麦琪:不过我觉得我这对我丈夫来说,
Maggie: But I'm afraid I behaved a little selfishly and, uh,
未免有点过于自私且不太明智,
stupidly towards my husband.
全哦丈夫他希望全家人时时刻刻都能聚在一起.
And all he wanted was just to have his family all together.
杰森:听起来你丈夫倒是个非常之人.
Jason: Sounds like a hell of a guy.
麦琪:那是!
Maggie: Oh, he is.
杰森:毫不夸张地讲,
Jason: Well, it's no exaggeration to say that he's married to a pretty
你丈夫他娶了一位很是漂亮的妻子
terrific lady.
麦琪:是吗?那可多谢了.
Maggie: Why thank you, sir.
杰森:据实而言,你也不用客气.
Jason: You are more than welcome.
麦琪:我真希望我丈夫能有你这么容易谈得来,劳埃.
Maggie: Boy I wish that my husband were as easy to talk to as you
are, Raul
杰森:真的吗?如果他就在现场,你打算跟他说些什么?
Jason: Really? If he were here right now what would you say to him?
麦琪:杰森,
Maggie: I'd say Jason,
我已经把那篇稿件赶完了,现在起,
I just wanted the last part of my story and from this moment on I'm here
我会全身心投入我们的家庭渡假的.
for some family fun.
杰森:嗯,这家旅馆有一项服务称作"客房服务",
Jason: ...The room service. Send it right to your room.
想吃什么他们都能给你送到房间里去,根本用不着换衣服.
You can eat it in your underwear.
服务生:不好意思.
Waiter: Whoops.
玛利亚:这就是颇具乡土风情的本地民居.
Malia: This is a typical old-fashioned native home.
迈克:嗯,是很不错.
Mike: Oh, uh nice.
玛利亚:喜欢吗?
Malia: You like it?
迈克:那当然!你认识这家人?
Mike: Yea, yea. Uh, do you know these people?
玛利亚:这就是我家.
Malia: I live here.
迈克:哇噢!你住在这,地方不错!
Mike: Oh, I love it. Oh, it's nice.
玛利亚:你爸妈可能都在等你回去呢?
Malia: So what time does your family expect you back?
迈克:不用担心,我又不是三岁小孩!!
Mike: Uhh, hey, what family?
玛利亚的妈妈:玛利亚,你回来啦!
Malia's Mom: Malia!
玛利亚:【夏威夷语】是我奶奶在叫我呢!
Malia: [Hawaiian] That's my grandmother.
迈克:你跟你奶奶住在一起?
Mike: You live with your grandmother?
玛利亚:还有我爷爷,妈妈,爸爸,叔叔!
Malia: And my grandfather, and my mother, and my father, and my uncle
迈克:不会吧?!你真的跟他们住在一起?
Mike: Oh gosh, you live with all these people?
玛利亚:嗯哼!
Malia: Uh huh.
迈克:我猜你肯定非常乐意搬出这地方!?
Mike: Oh well, bet you can't wait to move out of here.
玛利亚:为什么我要搬出去住呢?!
Malia: Why would I want to do that?
迈克:嗯,难道你不觉得跟这么多人住在一起,自己连点隐私都没有,甚至连自己想过的生活都没法过.
Mike: Well because, you know, you never have any privacy, you probably don't have a life of your own.
玛利亚:跟家人一起过我觉得很开心,没了他们倒叫人没着没落的.
Malia: Well it wouldn't be any fun without my family.
孩童:Aloha,嗨!
Child: Aloha, hi!
迈克:你有个小妹妹!?
Mike: Oh hi! You didn't tell me you had a little sister.
玛利亚:她不是我妹妹,是我女儿.露娜,
Malia: No, this is my daughter. Lena, this is Mike.
这位是迈克叔叔.迈克叔叔从很远的地方来看我们.给叔叔打个招呼吧!
He came all the way from the mainland to visit us. Mike, this is Lena.
迈克:原来这样啊!?
Mike: How's it going?
杰森:小声点,看看孩子们都在干嘛.嘘-嘘-嘘!
Jason: Oh wait, gotta check on the kids. SHHH.
麦琪:不好意思.
Maggie: Sorry.
杰森:快点!快点!
Jason: Go go go.
麦琪:本睡着了,迈克还没回来.要不要叫醒开萝尔.
Maggie: Ben's asleep and Mike's still out. Oh, we should wake her up.
开萝尔:鲍比!你不是说好要给我天天打电话的吗!!
Carol: Bobby! You were supposed to call me every Oh, oh I'm sorry,
噢,对不起,您等会.
hold on a sec, mom it's for you.
妈妈,找你的.要是鲍比打过来,
If Bobby calls tell him I'm out, tell him I'll be out tomorrow too,
就告诉他我不在,出去忙了!!
tell him I've got plans. Big plans.
杰森:晚安,乖女儿!
Jason: Good night.
麦琪:嗨,是苏珊吗?嗨,不不不,
Maggie: Hello? Susan, hi. No, no, no, no, I can hear you just fine. Good.
我明白你在说什么.嗯,你说什么?我的报道全国转载,
What? My story went national? Oh, you're kidding this is fabulous.
你是在拿我开玩笑吧!真没想到,没错这种机会千载难逢!需要我采访谁?
Once in a lifetime is right! What other interview? Uh huh. Well ok, ok.
那好吧,文章几时要?后天?!
When do they need it by? Uh huh. Day after tomorrow?
那我现在就要往回赶?!我知道很重要,我知道!好,
Oh, Susan, that means I'd have to come back right now.
那就这样,我马上回去.实在对不起,亲爱的.
Well I know its important, I know it's important, ok, ok, hold on. Honey?
杰森:Aloha!
Jason: Aloha.
电视节目:毛利岛,家庭渡假的理想之所,欢迎各位光临.
TV: Maui the perfect place for the ideal family vacation.
杰森:嘿,回来的是不是有点早啊,迈克?!
Jason: Yeah, right. Early night tonight, Mike?
迈克:那当然.
Mike: Yeah, it sure was.
杰森:到底怎么了?
Jason: What happened?
迈克:唉,算了吧,说了你也不明白.
Mike: Ah, forget it, Dad, you wouldn't understand.
杰森:那你说说看?
Jason: Well try me, what's it about?
迈克:全都是女人!
Mike: Women.
杰森:你说得没错,说了我也不明白!!
Jason: Yeah, you're right, I probably wouldn't understand.
迈克:爸爸,
Mike: See Dad, I went out with this girl and she was beautiful,
我今天一下午都跟那个漂亮女孩在一起,她真的是美若天仙,
she was gorgeous, she was perfect Dad,
但直到最后我才发现她根本不是个"女孩"
and the only thing is she turned out to be not a girl.
杰森:那是什么?
Jason: What?
迈克:她现在只能算作"女人"
Mike: She, she was a woman.
杰森:那么你说的这个"女人"今年有多大年纪?
Jason: Well how old was this woman?
毛利:十七岁而已!
Mike: Seventeen.
杰森:这样啊,那她应该算是"女孩".
Jason: Oh, she's a girl.
迈克:事情不是你想的那样,她现在有个小女儿,已经身为人母啦!
Mike: No, Dad, she has a girl.
杰森:不过,她仍应算作"女孩".
Jason: She has a girl.
迈克:不管怎么说,玛利亚她有个小孩!!
Mike: This girl/woman, Malia, she has a kid!
杰森:迈克,你是说这位姑娘有个孩子,
Jason: Well this girl/woman with a kid Mike,
那她是不是已经结婚了,她丈夫呢?
does she also happen to have a husband, too?
迈克:这我也不知道.
Mike: Well, not anymore.
杰森:什么,你也不知道?!
Jason: Well define not anymore?
迈克:事情是这样的,她很小的时候就结了婚,
Mike: Well see, she got married really young and this dude turned out
而跟她结婚的那小子只不过想玩玩她而已,
to be one of those guys who just wanted to party and mess around all the
后来就跑出来到处拈花惹草,
time. You know, one of those guys only thinks about himself,
不务正业.倒难为了她!
you know the type.
杰森:明白!
Jason: Kind of, yeah.
迈克:爸爸,当我亲眼见到玛利亚跟她女儿呆在一起,
Mike: Yea, well, Dad,
感觉真是令人难以置信.
seeing Malia standing there with her little girl was weird.
杰森:这为什么?
Jason: Why?
迈克:爸爸,老实说我也曾经约过好几个女孩,可往往我才是那个跟此有关的孩子.
Mike: Dad in all the dating I've done which, let's face it, is considerable, usually the only kid involved is me.
杰森:迈克,你终于明白了,
Jason: Well, what you're realizing Mike is that every girl you date is
跟你约会的女孩要么是某人的女儿,要么是别人的姐妹.
a person; she's always going to be somebody's daughter, or sister.
迈克,还有可能是别人的母亲.
Mike: Or mother.
本:嘿,开萝尔!
Ben: Hey Carol!
开萝尔:别大喊大叫的,本.
Carol: Stop yelling, Ben.
本:妈妈和爸爸打算要去机场,你要不要也去送送妈妈.
Ben: Mom and Dad wanted to check and see if you wanted to go with us take Mom to the airport.
开萝尔:你说什么?
Carol: What?
本:你要去机场送妈妈吗?
Ben: Are you coming to the airport or not?
开萝尔:我已经跟妈妈道过别了!
Carol: No! I said goodbye already.
本:开萝尔,晒晒太阳你的皮肤会更好看的,好好享受日光浴吧.嗨,开萝尔,瞧瞧,哈德利过去了.抓紧机会,千万别放过,老姐!!
Ben: You know Carol, you'll get a better tan if you wait until the sun finishes coming up. Hey Carol, look, it's Hadley. What a coinkydink, eh, Carol?
哈德利:嗨!
Hadley: Hi!
开萝尔:嗨!
Carol: Hi!
哈德利:怎么今天早上你有空?
Hadley: So you weren't busy this morning?
开萝尔:昨天你不是说今天你要休息吗?
Carol: Oh, gee, was it this morning you said that this was your day off
是店里让你到游泳池接待客人的?
when the hotel let you use the guests with the pool?
我是说你来游泳池为住客服务?
Uh, the pool with the guests.
杰森:唉,本,你能不能别老拿着那玩意对着我们,行不行?
Jason: Well, okay then. Ben, can you point that thing somewhere else please?
本:这你就不懂了吧?!此时此刻才是最精彩的.
Ben: Ah, this is where the mushy stuff starts anyway.
麦琪:亲爱的,实在对不起!
Maggie: Oh honey, I'm so sorry.
杰森:有什么呀!甭担心!
Jason: Sorry.
麦琪:你不怪我吗?
Maggie: This is where the mushy stuff starts.
杰森:(低声自语)
Jason: (mumbling)
麦琪:真的很抱歉,我也没办法,单位老是催!!
Maggie: Me too. And I'm really sorry I'm so needed at the paper.
杰森:错不在你,事业上的成功终于让你如愿以偿,我也很是替你高兴.
Jackie: It's not your fault you're so successful.
麦琪:你真的这么想?
Maggie: Are you serious?
杰森:没什么,顶多就是无法在暖暖的日光浴下舒舒服服地放松一下,
Jason: So what are you going to be missing for a couple days of relaxing
不过也会和地道的夏威夷乡土晚宴失之交臂.
in the sun? Big lu'au that I made reservations for? Me? I'm kidding.
我很好,下次我们一家人一定有机会再次出来渡假的.
I'm fine. I know someday we're going to have a family vacation together.
麦琪:那当然!
Maggie: I'm sure we will.
本:嘿,爸爸,想不想跟我一起去骑马?
Ben: Hey Dad, you want to go horseback riding with me?
杰森:本,爸爸已经好长时间没骑过马了,现在都不知道还会不会骑马.
Jason: Well I don't know Ben, the last time I went horseback riding
本:嘿,爸爸,你看,那不是鲍比来了吗?
Ben: Hey Dad! Look it's Bobby!
鲍比:嗨,西维尔大夫!嗨,本!你们好吗?
Bobby: Hey Dr. Seaver! Hey Ben!
杰森:你怎么也来了?
Jason: What are you doing here?
鲍比:想给开萝尔一个惊喜.
Bobby: I came to surprise Carol.
本:爸爸,快给我多买点录影带,好戏就要开始了!
Ben: Dad, quick you gotta buy me some more video tape.
导游:【日语】再会!再会!回见!
Tour guide: [Japanese] Bye bye! Bye bye!
玛利亚:你还想不付钱就参加我的旅行团?
Malia: Are you trying to join my tour without paying again?
迈克:我也不知道自己想干什么?
Mike: I don't know what I'm trying to do.
玛利亚:我却知道!!
Malia: I sensed that about you.
开萝尔:嗯,这本书写得不错,
Carol: Well, that's fundamentally true.
基本符合史实.不过,
But it's generally conceded that the Roman Empire fell when the
普遍的看法是,由于知识分子只顾着自己享受声色犬马之娱,
intelligentsia shifted its priorities from concern of the welfare of the
而对帝国事务却漠不关心,最后才导致了罗马帝国的衰亡.
empire to totally selfish and hedonistic pleasures.
哈德利:你能说得详细点吗?
Hadley: Tell me about it.
开萝尔:本,你在这晃来晃去的想干什么?
Carol: Ben, what are you doing here?
本:好戏登场喽!
Ben: Now!
鲍比:开萝尔,哼,你好啊!!
Bobby: Yo, Carol!
开萝尔:鲍比你也来了!
Carol: Bobby!
本:你们俩就这点本事??
Ben: Is that it? Is that the best you guys can do?
鲍比:原来你背着我偷偷摸摸地干这龌龊事,啊?!
Bobby: Oh, so this is what's been going on behind my back, huh?
开萝尔:没你想的那样.我整整呆在房间里等了七天,
Carol: It is not,
你连个电话也没打一个!!
I've spent seven days waiting for that phone to ring which it never once did.
鲍比:那是因为我在加班,
Bobby: That's because I was working overtime saving money time to come
想挣足路费来看你.
here and surprise you.
哈德利:嗨,我是哈德利·巴尼斯.
Hadley: Hi, I'm Hadley Barnes.
鲍比:嗨,我快被你气死了.
Bobby: Hi, I'm really steamed.
开萝尔:鲍比,干什么呢你?!
Carol: Bobby!
本:嘿,大家开心一点嘛,别老是拉着脸!
Ben: Hey you guys, say cheese!
杰森:你好,我是西维尔大夫,本来说好了有五个人参加夏威夷乡土晚宴的,
Jason: Hello, yea, this is Dr.
现在我想退订.真不好意思,我实在是没办法,
Seaver, I had a reservation for five for your lu'au tonight and, uh,
孩子们各有各的事,我妻子也被公司急急忙忙地召回.
I have to cancel that. Yeah, I'm sorry, too.
嗯,你说的没错,我妻子是名记者,
Well, who knows where the kids are and my wife had to go back to her
所以呢,只能麻烦您了,谢谢!
job. So. Reporter. So, anyway, just cancel it, Ok? Thank you.
本:爸爸,爸爸,
Ben: Dad, dad, the horseback riding was fantastic! You should have come!
骑马太好玩了,叫你去你不去,现在后悔了吧!?
I got this really neat horse that looked like the black stallion only
我刚才骑了一匹通体黑亮的高头大马,不过它屁股旁边有一块却是白的.
it's butt was white!
杰森:真的,那这下你可玩好了……
Jason: Well, yeah...
本:噢,对了!夏威夷乡土晚宴什么时候开始啊?到那里我们能干点什么?
Ben: So what time's the lu'au? I mean, what do they do there?
有好吃的吗?嗯,爸爸,快说啊!!
Do they have a lot of food? Tell me! Tell me!
杰森:本,你总是……
Jason: You're quite a guy Ben
本:怎么了,爸爸你说我怎么了?
Ben: Why, what'd I do?
杰森:嗯,我觉得你天生就是个乐观主义者,整天无忧无虑的,爸爸好羡慕你!!
Jason: Well, you are the eternal optimist.
本:你觉得这样不好吗?
Ben: You mean I need glasses?
杰森:当然不是!那好,
Jason: I mean you and I are going to go to that Lu'au and we're going
今天晚上咱爷俩一块去吃夏威夷乡土晚宴,你赶紧去换衣服!
to have a great time so you go get changed, ok? Yes, Dr. Seaver.
你好,我是西维尔大夫,
I just canceled that reservation for five to the Lu'au and I'd like to
刚才取消了5个人的订座,现在我想请你再改成两个人的.两位就够了,
reinstate it for two please. No, no, no, she didn't come back.
我妻子不来.他们抓了一头猪,
What they do is they take a pig and they stuff an apple in its mouth
在它嘴里塞上苹果,然后把它埋在地里用火烤.
and they put him in the ground and they roast it.
本:活生生地就烤!
Ben: While it's still alive?
杰森:当然不是,待会你自己好好瞧瞧!
Jason: No, no, see
本:爸爸,你看,鲍比也过来了!
Ben: Hey Dad, there's Bobby!
杰森:吆!鲍比!你也过来想和我们一起参加夏威夷乡土晚宴?
Jason: Yo, Bobby! Why don't you come and join us for the Lu'au?
鲍比:不要因为你女儿甩了我,就装出一副好人样,
Bobby: Oh, you don't have to be nice to me just because Carol cut my heart
我可不吃你这套.
out and stomped on it.
杰森:你别难过,西维尔家的女人对男人都这样.
Jason: Nothing personal Bobby,
西维尔大夫的订座.
all the women in our family tree treat men that way. Ah, Seaver Party?
服务生:嗯,我记得,一共两位是吧?!
Waiter: Uh, yes, party of two, I remember.
杰森:你都看见了,现在有三个人.
Jason: Well, there will be three now.
本:是啊,我姐姐被气跑了,哥哥也溜的不见踪影,妈妈又回去忙公司里的事情,自然就剩下我们了.
Ben: Yeah, my sisters sulking and my brother disappeared again and my Mom flew home
服务生:嗯,她是一名记者,那自然很忙啦.这个就是你们的餐桌!!
Waiter: I heard she's a reporter. Table for three.
本:很好!!这地方离跳热舞的姑娘最近,好位置!!
Ben: All right! I'm going to be able to get real close to the hula girls!
杰森:谢谢!
Jason: That'll be perfect, thank you.
开萝尔:他坐在我的位置上干嘛?!
Carol: What's he doing in my seat?
杰森:开萝尔,我们还以为你不来了呢!
Jason: Carol, we didn't know you were coming.
开萝尔:我当然会过来的.我才不会让他搅了我的假期.
Carol: Well, uh, I'm certainly not going to let him ruin my vacation.
杰森:先生,打扰一下,您能不能给我们换张四人座的桌子?
Jason: Well, we have a table for four.
鲍比:不用了,我可以走!
Bobby: I can go.
开萝尔:请便!
Carol: It's up to you.
杰森:四人桌,嗯,没听到吗?
Jason: Four of you, eh
服务生:等这个小伙子决定好了再说!
Man: I was waiting for the younger gentleman respond.
杰森:留下吧!
Jason: You stay.
服务生:这边走!
Man: This way.
鲍比:这个?
Bobby: So?
开萝尔:这个什么?
Carol: So?
鲍比:你男朋友呢?
Bobby: Where's your boyfriend?
开萝尔:哈德利根本不是我男朋友,我们只是在一起讨论罗马帝国的衰亡.
Carol: Hadley is not my boyfriend, we were merely discussing the fall of Rome.
鲍比:开萝尔,别装了,那小子给你又是涂抹润滑油又是按摩的!
Bobby: Carol, that man was greasing your back.
开萝尔:你怎么老往歪处想?!
Carol: Don't make it something gross!
鲍比:我?我的学习没你好,
Bobby: Oh, me? Look,
但是我亲眼目睹有人追求你.
I might be slow compared to you but I know what I saw.
你既漂亮又聪明,
I saw a guy coming on to you.
你或许对一群男生围着你转习以为常,可我就是受不了.
Now you're so beautiful and smart maybe you're used to that but I'm not.
开萝尔:你说我很漂亮?
Carol: Beautiful?
鲍比:一直以来,我都很担心失去你,但没想到竟然这么快.
Bobby: I was always afraid of losing you. I never thought it would be so soon.
开萝尔:你还担心失去我?!
Carol: You afraid of losing me?
鲍比:那当然!你要我赌咒发誓吗?
Bobby: Why wouldn't I?
开萝尔:原来如此!我一直还以为,算了不说这个.
Carol: I don't know, I always thought that I was you're absolutely right,
总之,你说的完全对,亲爱的
Bobby, honey.
杰森:尽情享用我们的夏威夷乡土晚宴吧!
Jason: Enjoy the lu'au.
迈克:嘿,大家好!这是露娜,玛利亚的女儿!
Mike: Hey everybody, it's Luna, Malia's little girl.
大家:嗨!
Everyone: Hi!
迈克:她妈妈在上班,等一会就会来看我们.
Mike: Yeah, see her Mom has to work, and, uh,
你别玩儿银餐具.现在由我来照看她一会.
she's going to meet us a little bit later.
嗨,
Come on, don't play with the silver ware.
露娜,别乱跑!
Hey, you gotta keep your eye on her all the time. Hey Luna, no!
杰森:服务生,您好!
Jason: Waiter! Excuse me, I hate to say it,
实在对不起,我也不想这样;不过,您能再帮我们换一下餐桌吗?
but I think we're going to need uh.
服务生:那你们坐在那边,那张餐桌总共可以坐十二人,这下够用了吧!
Waiter: Why don't you just take that table over there, it seats up to twelve.
杰森:嗯,行!谢谢您!
Jason: Oh, yea, thank you.
迈克:过来啊,露娜,别玩沙子!我们去那边,快点啊!
Mike: Hey come on Luna, help play with the sand! We're over here, come on!
杰森:迈克,我个人认为你根本适应不了单身妈妈.
Jason: Mike, I thought you weren't ready for women with kids.
迈克:是吗?不过,
Mike: Yeah, well you know,
爸爸,我记得你曾经说过,看女人不能光看外表,
I was thinking about what you said about there being more to girls than
还要注重她的内在美,是不是?
just the way they look.
杰森:你也这么认为?
Jason: You thought that?
迈克:那当然!每个女人迟早总会生孩子的,
Mike: Yeah! You know,
现在就有,好像也不是什么坏事,
I figured that everyone eventually ends up with women with kids,
对不对,爸爸?
can't be that bad, can it?
杰森:话虽如此,但是,
Jason: Well, Mike, you know being part of a family isn't always easy but
迈克,做爸爸可没你想的那么容易.
it's always.
迈克:露娜,别!!
Mike: Luna, no!
杰森:看你还胡吹大气?!
Jason: Interesting.
麦琪:帅哥,你好.
Maggie: Hi handsome.
杰森:我结婚了,你要干什么?
Jason: Married. What?
本:妈妈!!
Ben: Mom.
麦琪:先听我说,我在檀香山换飞机时,
Maggie: Before you say a word, when I changed planes in Oahu,
给公司打了个电话,
I called Susan at the paper and I told her that my family was just as
我对苏珊说,我的家庭比我的前程更加重要.
important as my career.
杰森:所以你又回来了!?
Jason: You're here!
麦琪:杰森,先听我把话讲完!!
Maggie: Jason, have you been listening to me?
杰森:苏珊她同意了?
Jason: You told Susan that?
麦琪:亲爱的,你一句一句慢慢说行不行?
Maggie: Honey, are you one question off?
杰森:我当然在听了.新闻稿可以推迟发表?
Jason: Of course I'm listening. So, the story can wait?
麦琪:不是的,她没说可以!
Maggie: No, she didn't say that.
杰森:谁这么说的?
Jason: Who?
麦琪:苏珊啊,还有谁?
Maggie: Susan.
杰森:究竟怎么回事?
Jason: What?
麦琪:她没说新闻稿可以推迟几天发表,
Maggie: She didn't say the story could wait.
她只是告诉我公司非常重视这篇新闻稿,
She said if I didn't realize how much the paper was counting on me then
所以要我必须尽快返回.
there was no reason for me to hurry back.
杰森:但是你却回来了!
Jason: You're here!
麦琪:没错!那份工作我不干了!
Maggie: Yes! I quit!
杰森:你把工作辞了?亲爱的,你没必要如此牺牲,赶快给苏珊回电话吧!
Jason: You quit! Your job? No, honey, you got to call her back.
麦琪:行啊!
Maggie: Ok.
杰森:你是说…?
Jason: Ok, what?
麦琪:不是,我在跟你开玩笑呢!!
Maggie: No, I'm kidding.
杰森:你没有辞职,还是不愿给苏珊回电话??
Jason: Kidding about quitting or kidding about calling?
麦琪:不是,我真的不想再干那份工作了,所以就没必要给她回电话.
Maggie: No, I did quit my job and I'm not calling anyone.
杰森:你失业了,这样不好吧!
Jason: You're unemployed; I don't think that's good.
其实,你可以……
You know, maybe you should.
麦琪:我明白你要说什么,杰森!
Maggie: Oh, Jason, shut up.
找另一份工作要比找个幸福美满的家庭容易得多.
Finding another job is easier than finding another family.
本:跟我无关!!
(唱歌,演员们在旁边表演歌舞)
00:21:14,200
Ben: It wasn't me. (sing ,People are playing.)